hi everyone uh thanks for joining in to
this webinar uh can you all please raise
your hand if you can hear me and see my
screen okay so I can see some hands so
yeah uh as I said uh welcome to this
webinar on mastering requirements
management uh and tricentis tosa
although this webinar is for 1 hour
duration um if it might not take that
much of time uh it's not a very big
topic but uh it's an important topic
within pren TSA uh we will try to stick
with the topic today uh which is
requirements uh management which will
revolve around the requirement section
in tosa uh if you have got any questions
you can raise your hand or you can use
the QA q& a section to just write your
question down and uh I will try to
answer it within the session if not I
will uh reach out to you later on uh if
uh you have some specific question
around this topic or uh any other topic
within uh the trentis tosa
tool so yeah uh we'll get started um
while people are joining in
so let's go to tosa and then we will
start with the requirements section okay
so uh talking a little bit brief about
uh what is a require ments and why it is
important and U how tosa tries to
integrate this uh particular feature
into its tool right so requirements as
we know um any any application you are
working on or any business for that
matter has got um requirements right uh
which comes either from the client's
customers or from uh the product owners
uh so all the testing which we do are um
somehow linked to the requirements of
the application and then the development
is also done based on these requirements
and then testing is done to basically
confirm that uh these um whatever has
been developed as a feature or as an
application meets the requirements
because that's the ultimate goal of any
application which uh is being built uh
it meets the uh expectations of the
client and uh it meets the requirements
of how the product is being developed
and how it should look for the end user
right so every product or every
application has got requirements and um
as part of testing it's very important
that we link uh whatever test cases we
are building uh either be it manual
testing or automation testing that has
to be um a link to all I mean all of the
test cases should link back to some
requirement M otherwise we would never
be able to tell whether um we are
actually covering any requirements if we
are just writing test cases and never
looking back at our requirements so
there has to be a a traceability between
your requirements and your test cases
which you are developing and then uh
when you are executing then also you
need to look back at your requirements
and see um how much coverage you are
providing through that particular
execution how much is passing how much
is failing because at the end of the day
uh
the the testing uh which you are doing
uh will be marked as uh successful or
not successful based on how much
coverage you provide to to your
requirements and uh what is the pass
coverage and based on that then the
project uh or the project owners uh can
decide whether they want to go ahead
with a particular feature being released
or big whe whether the product should be
released to the clients or customers
based on your past fail criteria and
then your coverage of the requirements
right so everything ties back to the
requirements uh it is a essential part
of uh the whole development life cycle
and even the software testing life cycle
right so everything starts from the
requirements where we analyze the
requirements and then we build our test
cases which can cover those requirements
so uh the this is all a background about
what is requirements and why it is
important then coming to tosa so tosa
has got a section called requirements um
and this is provided uh to build your
own requirements okay and then uh all
these requirements which are built uh
can be easily linked to all the other
sections in tosa okay so all the other
sections which I mean is uh the
execution list the test cases
uh you can even link your test case
design so these are the objects which
can be linked to a particular
requirement and then um at the end of
the day um the product owners or the
project uh stakeholders can come to this
requirement section and they can uh have
u a view of your project how it is going
because it will uh act as a dashboard
for them where they can see uh what is
the requirement coverage what is the
execution state
um and how much has been covered through
these requirements for the specific
project right so the requirements uh
section not only holds the requirements
uh for the project it also acts as a
dashboard for the project where um
anybody can come here and they can see
um what are the requirements and what
are what is the requirement coverage
current requirement coverage what is the
execution state so it also asks like a
report for all the business stakeholders
um when they looking at the automation
from a tosa perspective
okay so um the requirement section is uh
already there on the menu right so if
you if you're not able to see that
section then you can always go back to
uh this SE section menu and then you can
choose requirements and that will come
up uh in your
screen so um it is also part of the main
project which uh has been created you
can see the requirement section is there
by default like all the other sections
if you create any particular um
component folder like this then also you
can add your own requirements section
inside that or requirements folder
inside that okay so any any project uh
which is there inside uh the workspace
you can create your own requirement
section
so starting off uh with the requirements
and how you start working with the
requirements the first thing which uh
you need to do in the requirement
section is you need to create a
requirement structure in tosa okay which
is uh quite important when you are
working on a real-time project you
should have a structure through which uh
you can design your or you can build
your requirements for that specific
application could be working on multiple
projects at the same time or multiple
applications so you should have a
structure which will display the actual
uh requirements of that particular
application or that particular project
right so um how do you build your
requirement structure so first of all
you should create a folder okay so that
folder will uh constitute of all the
requirements for a particular
application so
for this session let's consider this
application vehicle insurance okay so we
will create some requirements for this
particular application today so I'm
going to call this uh vehicle
insurance similarly you can have
multiple uh folders now how do you want
to structure is completely dependent on
um your requirement your project
requirement so you can structure it
based on um the applic
itself or you can break it down into
different folders based on your
functionality or you can have uh
something like uh if you are having
different releases then you can build uh
or create folders based on your release
Cycles so you can have multiple folders
for all the different release cycles and
then you can build your requirements in
those um in those folders right so how
you build it completely depends on you
uh I'm going to use this as as the main
project folder inside this once you have
the requirements folder then you create
a requirement set okay so all the
requirements which you want to create
should always be inside a requirement
set so a requirement set is like a
collection of requirements okay so which
contains different requirements it can
hold a different requirements and you
can build number of requirement sets
again within the folder so there are
multiple levels of uh hierarchy between
uh inside the requirement section and
you can structure them as per your
project
requirements okay so uh this is One
requirement set um as you can see now
inside this uh we can have multiple uh
requirements right
so if we look at this particular
application um you can see we have got
different um different vehicle types
like automobile truck motorcycle camper
right so each of them then have their
own um application flow right so every
vehicle type will have its own
requirements uh it will have its own
weightage and then it will have uh its
own test cases right so it's good idea
to have different requirements for all
these different vehicle types okay so
inside requirements set then uh we can
create some requirements like
automobile and then for
camper
and truck and
motorcycle okay so this is how you
structure your requirements uh you first
create a folder then a set then your
individual ual requirements and then
each individual requirement will be
linked to its own test cases okay
so uh this is the uh structure of how
every requirement should be built right
the next thing is coming to weight right
so uh there is a column called weight uh
in your requirements whenever you create
any any requirement the default weight
is always one okay so that's set by tosa
itself you can always go ahead and
change this weight now uh what is this
weight uh it's basically the weightage
of any particular requirement within the
application okay so in the application
every every requirement or every
functionality will have got will have
different weightage which means it will
have different uh different risk
compared to other functionality or other
require requirements now how do you
calculate that risk okay so it it comes
to the business risk so if a particular
functionality fails then what impact
does it have on um the end users so that
calculates the business risk right and
there are multiple factors which can uh
constitute this risk but this is the
whole uh or the main purpose of uh
defining the business risk or weightage
of a particular requirement right so not
every requirement will have the same
weightage okay so for me the automobile
section has got the highest weightage
because I think that uh this carries the
most uh most risk uh in the application
and also uh it is being used by the
maximum customers and that is why it is
got more importance and if it fails then
it has got more risk to my business than
compared to some other uh requirements
or other functionality okay so what I I
can do is I can have uh different uh
weightage for each of my requirements
okay based on this could be based on
either your understanding of the
application or you can talk to your
product owners your uh your uh project
managers on uh What uh what best
weightage could be put on this this
sometimes are also done by the product
owners themselves but if they are not
doing it themselves then uh that
automation testers can speak to them and
then decide what weightage they want to
put for all these requirements which has
been created okay so uh this uh
weightage you can always change
initially when you create it uh it is
set to one but there is no right or
wrong or how you set what number you put
uh it's all dependent on um how you want
to use them okay so uh in general um
when we create it is one and then uh
when you want to increase or decrease it
should be on a scale of 1 to five it is
just based on some best practice as I
said there is no hard rule that you
should put this number but uh you should
think like one is um like the least
weightage and five is the greatest
weightage when you are trying to wait
requirements based on their importance
or their risk factor okay so here you
can see automobile has got the highest
weightage um then the truck then
motorcycle then camper right and
accordingly then the contribution
percentage which is here will change you
can see U automobile contributes the
maximum to this particular requirement
Set uh which is
45% and then depending on the weightage
it will autocalculate all this
contribution percentage okay um there
are some other columns like coverage
specified execution State these are all
gray right now because I haven't linked
any executions here or I haven't linked
any test cases so the coverage specified
and execution state are all gray which
means they are by default showing 100%
because nothing has been linked as of
now okay so uh this is how you can put
some basic weightage uh uh with the
weight column uh then there is two other
factors which can be used to calculate
the weightage automatically in
tosa and uh these two columns uh they
represent two different factors one is
frequency class and one is damage class
okay so there are two ways of putting
weight to your requirement either you
can if you know the weight then you put
the weight directly here if you don't
know the weight you want tosa to
calculate it uh based on different
factors then you use frequency class and
damage class okay so now um what is
frequency class and what is damage class
so coming to frequency class uh
frequency class of a particular
requirement is uh the frequency of that
particular requirement being used by the
end users in your application okay so
any particular functionality which is
being used uh maximum uh or the most
number of times um in a particular cycle
or or by the analysis of the application
uh when you do a proper analysis of
which part of the application is being
you most used by your end users so you
can find that out so that's that's
basically the frequency class okay so
the frequency of uh the functionality
being used uh by by the end users and
that will uh Define your frequency class
similarly the damage class um is
basically the damage uh which it will do
if this particular requirement stops
working or uh there is some problem with
this functionality it's not working then
what damage it will do to uh the overall
uh project uh from the end user
perspective um or what damage it will do
to the um to the maybe to the client to
the customer
so that defines the damage class okay so
you have to think from that perspective
whenever you are putting these numbers
into your requirements okay so um for
example of as I said automobile carries
the maximum weightage so I I put um
again frequency classes five your damage
classes five um again here I always use
a scale of 1 to five whenever I'm
putting these numbers you have to be
consistent across the requirements uh
whenever you are trying to uh put these
numbers because you cannot uh put a
scale of one to five for One requirement
and then for another requirement you put
a scale or use a scale of 1 to 10 you
have to be consistent if you are using 1
to 10 as the scale then use it
throughout all your requirements if
you're using scale 1 to five then you
use one to five for all the other
requirements okay so there has to be a
consistency otherwise um or your
requirement coverage and everything
would be all over the place okay so here
um I can then uh put a frequency and
damage class and then uh based on my
understanding or uh based on the
information which I receive from the
product owners or the business owners
right so I put uh these numbers and then
what tosa will do is it will put some
calculation and it will automatically
update the weight of each requirement
okay uh it does it using a formula and
that formula is
uh 2 to the power of frequency class
multiplied by 2 to the power of damage
class okay so basically it is 2^ of 5
into 2^ of 5 which comes around 1024
similarly the same um calculation is
applied across all the other
requirements okay and that gives you a
weightage uh which is the weightage of
that particular requirement okay and you
can see here automobile now has got the
maximum weightage because uh the
frequency and damage class are higher
for this compared to all the other
requirements okay so these are the two
ways uh you can calculate your weight
for your requirements it's important
because uh it then comes back to other
framework or the pillar on which tosa is
built on it is built on basically two
pillars of Frameworks one is the modular
framework which it uses and then the
risk-based testing okay so tosa is built
all around risk-based testing where the
testing um is optimized to uh cover the
maximum coverage to have the maximum
coverage and also provide the best
possible or efficient risk based testing
okay so uh you can um you can design
your test cases so that uh it will have
the maximum coverage but the minimum
number of test cases uh which has got
the highest risk okay so that's
basically uh which um implies the risk
based testing which tosa is built on and
which you can also Implement using tosa
for your project okay so it's important
to have some weight either you have the
static weight or you have the
calculation of frequency and damage
class
okay so uh this is how you wait your
requirements uh now another thing which
you can do is for each requirement if
you go to the properties okay so here uh
in the properties you will
see first of all the status uh here also
you can see the status how much is
passed how much is failed and and uh
what is not linked you can see here it
is showing uh currently is all zero
right and 100% which means it is not
linked to any test cases so that's the
status of this particular
requirement um there's calculation
results all everything is zero right now
and then there is a requirement type
okay so by default for all the
requirements the requirement type is
requirement but um if you want to have a
classification of your requirements in
your project if you want to have
different requirements for maybe
different releases Cycles or maybe
different U application types uh depends
uh what you want okay so that can be
done uh at a project level okay so how
you can do that you can go to your main
project and then
um you you go to uh your project
settings
and here uh you can right click and then
when you right click you will see uh
there is an option called create
requirement type definition okay so this
will be some additional requirement type
definitions um and there is only one
requirement type definition right now
which is requirement okay but you can
add as many as you required for your
project just a minute so yeah oh sorry
so you need to go to properties
definition uh I clicked many times so it
created uh these many types of
requirement
definitions so you can name it as I said
U any type of requirement uh maybe you
can have functional requirements
right then um you can have nonfunctional
requirement
okay so like this you can uh create as
many requirement types as you want right
right now you can see I have three
different types one is created by
default the other two I have created
functional and nonf functional like this
you can have as many as you want uh
depending on what you want to create
okay and how you want to Define your
requirements so for now uh what I can do
is um
I can go ahead
and so um once we create those
requirement types right so if uh we want
to assign any particular requirement
types so we need to uh drag and drop
that particular requirement type
definition into our requirements okay
so go go to properties definition and
then come
here okay so if I want this to
be okay no I think it's the other way
around yeah so uh we need to drag and
drop the requirement into the
requirement type definition not the
other way around which I was trying so
now I have dragged the automobile into
the functional requirement and
motorcycle into the non-functional
requirement okay okay so if I now go
back and I look at automobile you will
see the requirement type as functional
requirement and motorcycle as
non-functional requirement the other two
are just requirement okay so this is
just a way of uh classifying or um
dividing your requirement into different
requirement types rather than just
keeping One requirement type you can
have multiple requir types so tosa
provides this uh unique feature
okay
um so this is uh this is how you can uh
do all the different requirement types
and then um the weightage we talked
about then um coming to the linking or
linking the requirements to different
object types or like test cases or
execution list right so we talked about
that now how you can do that so now
currently there is no uh test cases link
here that is why the coverage specified
is not uh it's by default 100% not
linked right that's the status of it so
what we can do uh we can go ahead and
now um link some test cases into our
requirements okay so for that you need
to have test cases built for that
obviously
and once you have that um you can
directly go ahead and either link one
test case or all the test cases so here
I have got a template instance you can
see which is built from a template of
vehicle insurance I can go ahead uh
either I can link these test cases
individually or I can directly link this
complete uh folder into a requirement
which is automobile okay you cannot link
your test cases to your a requirement
set it always has to be a to a
requirement so remember
that okay so now you will see that uh
the coverage specified uh will change
right so for requirement set it is uh
still not 100% because there are other
requirements within this requirement set
but for a a individual requirement you
can see it has now dragged it to 100%
right now how is that calculated
so the coverage specified uh has also
got its own calculation and something
will affect this percentage so let me
tell you how so now if I go back to
these test cases individual test cases
okay the most important uh thing in this
uh whenever you are linking your test
cases to your requirements is the work
state of your of your test case Okay so
this work state of the test case impacts
uh the coverage specified percentage on
the requirements dashboard so that is
why uh this work state has got three
states you can see here planned in work
and completed okay now every a work
state value has got um a particular
number assigned to it in tosa so if you
set the work state to plann then uh it
consider considers it as 20 % complete
if it is in work then it considers to be
50% and if you mark it as completed then
it is 100% okay so that's how it is um
assigned uh in tosa within tosa and
that's how it calculates also so if
currently all my test cases are marked
as completed and that is why the
coverage specified is 100% but if I go
ahead and change uh the work state of
one of these test cases to maybe in
work and then I change one of these test
test cases to plann then you will see my
requirement coverage will change okay so
now if I just look at the automobile
requirement you will see the coverage
specified went down to
87% okay and 30 133% is still not
covered so this is the requirement or
coverage specified percentage which
means it tells you what number of test
cases are already completed what are
still in progress what uh percentage of
test cases are U still not covered or
still not completed okay so all of it
impacts uh the coverage specified on
your dashboard so whenever you are
completing uh your test cases you should
always make sure that uh it is marked as
completed
okay now what is the um what is the
calculation so it is calculated uh based
on uh two factors one is relative weight
okay uh which is again um another column
and then that is Multiplied with the
work state as I said different workstate
a status has got different uh percentage
so it is Multiplied the weight and the
work state and then it comes to a number
which is the percentage so it is shown
in here
okay now um there are some default
columns in the requirement requirement
section but there are more columns you
can always go to column Chooser and add
more columns into this particular
dashboard so I was talking about
relative weight right
so that also um factors in in coverage
specified as I said so relative weight
um is like the weight of this particular
requirement compared to all the other
weights in the requirement set that
brings out the relative weight okay so
the coverage specified is relative
weight into M or multiplied by the work
state and that will uh give you the
coverage specified that's the
calculation
okay
um yeah so that's how you link your test
cases into your requirements right and
now uh coming back to let's go to our
requirements folder so that's that's the
that's how you link your test cases the
next thing is what you can link is your
execution list so that you get a
execution State here okay so for that
you need to have some execution list
okay so I've got this execution list you
can see here here uh for vehicle
insurance which contains all the test
cases now some of them are passed some
of them are failed some of them are not
executed in this particular execution
list okay so if I want to link this into
uh my
requirements then I can either uh link
the individual execution entries okay
one by one or I can also directly link
the complete execution list
okay so I can go ahead and uh drag it
into my requirement set okay so that
execution list will then be displayed uh
inside the requirement set okay and it
is linked to this particular requirement
set now and then you will see a proper
State uh execution state for your
requirements okay now you will see that
it is showing the execution ution state
which is 37% passed 30% uh failed 20%
not executed uh 133% maybe not linked
okay so that's that's the current state
uh execution state of your
requirement and this is the coverage
specified which is linked to your test
case uh status whether it is completed
whether it isn't planned or it is not
yet started okay so as you can see
overall uh this view will give uh any
project uh project manager or product
owner the overall status of the uh
current project automation project which
is going on so he can see what has been
executed uh what is the state and he can
also see how many test cases have been
created or has been U covered as part of
the requirements okay so it gives uh
them a complete picture of what is going
on currently within the automation
project and they can then take a call
based on that uh how they want to
proceed with the maybe the release cycle
or they want to extend or they want to
uh not release a particular feature so
it it gives them a very clear picture
and this should always be updated based
on your current project and what you are
currently working on and that depends on
how you link them and how you um update
your status of your test cases always
okay uh now there are some other columns
also present uh within requirements
apart from we talked about relative
weight uh we talked about C specified we
talked about execution state right so
apart from this also you have got some
um other columns okay
which might help you sometimes uh to uh
gauge what what is the maybe what what's
the requirement like we can also add the
requirement type here if we have got
different types so that is a column
called requirement type okay then
[Music]
um there is coverage executed so what
amount of um test cases have already
been executed you can also put
aggregated weight okay then required
test cases uh result aggregation uh that
will be at a requirement set level if
you have also linked test case design
then you can also add this particular
column okay so you can decide what
columns you want to have or remove any
column which you don't want to see here
okay um so you can see here the
requirement type this this is the
requirement type and then we can
collapse this we can see the coverage
executed okay um the aggregated weight
here and then uh the test case design so
we haven't linked any test case design
but uh if you have
got your test case design then you can
also link that here okay so let me see
here
okay um I don't have anything inside
this sheet because I have created a
class
here okay um it's not allowing me but
generally it is you just drag the test
sheet into the requir M and then it will
create a test case uh substitute link
which will then U link the design sheet
into the particular requirement okay so
maybe I um you can try and create a new
requirement sheet add some attributes
and instances and then try to link this
into a requirement set or uh into a
requirement I will check why it is not
adding but I will share um an update
maybe after the webinar on why it was
not linking okay but that's how you can
also link the test case design apart
from the execution and uh execution list
and the test cases but the most
important are
um the test cases and the execution list
because they provide you with the
coverage specified and execution State
percentage
okay um so those are all the call
columns uh which can be added to to the
requirement section and um that will
provide you with the overall project
estate um apart from this so what else
is there let
me yeah so if there are any uh changes
which which is happening uh maybe on at
execution list level or something has
changed at your test cases you have
added more test cases or uh some you
have executed a new set of execution
entries right so in those kind of
scenarios what will happen sometimes if
you're working in a um multi-user
project where multiple users are using
the same project and everybody's
executing the test cases and everybody
is developing their test cases so the
requirement uh percentages will keep on
changing
okay and it might happen that you will
not have the updated values always in
this requirements okay if it is a big
project uh in those kind of scenarios
there is also an option to update the
values if you don't have the latest
values then you can always right click
on the requirement set and you can click
on update values it will throw you this
warning that it will take some time
based on how big your project is how
many test cases you have it might take
some time but usually doesn't take so
long okay so um what it will do is it
will recalculate everything okay uh
based on whatever is linked to this
requirement set it will recalculate and
it will display you the latest values
right here okay so that's how you can um
basically update your requirements um
all and all the calculations which are
linked to this particular
requirement
okay uh there's also an feature from
where you can um also import your
requirements from uh some external
documents if you if you're working on
like a Microsoft Word uh for that uh you
can do is there is an option
okay let me me
see okay so if um you go into the folder
level for your requirements right and
you right click there you will see
there's an option import requirements
from word captions okay so this uh will
basically uh allow you to import your
requirements from a document file but uh
it has to be uh in a certain structure
that you can find out from
um from the tosar documentation you can
see that is a a a sample Word document
which has been provided okay so there uh
you need to have a
particular almost um different headings
for all your different uh requirements
and then within that you can have sub
requirements uh you can have some text
so it has to be in a particular format
uh then only it will um allow you to
import that particular document and then
uh that can be used to build uh your
requirements from that external document
okay
um so that's how you can import the doc
um your requirements from the Microsoft
Word into tosa
Commander um what
else okay um
also you can can create different
requirement set links okay um so I
showed you one way of um linking your
require requirements to your execution
list right or your um or your test cases
uh you what you can also do is you can
create these requirement set links okay
which uh will allow you to
uh link your requirements to your test
cases or your uh execution lists so
there are two ways of doing it um you
can use any of them um as you
like okay so here if we
look you can see here uh if you right
click on the requirement the individual
requirement there is an option called
create test case link okay so um as I
said you can do it both ways either you
can directly drag and drop which I find
it easier all the time I directly drag
um test cases into the requirement but
you can always create this test case
links okay uh and then uh drag your test
case into this particular link so that
it up it links uh it links the
requirements into this particular test
case link you need to rename this um and
then you need to link it to the
respective uh test cases okay but um as
I said dragging and dropping is the
mostly the easier way of uh linking the
requirements to the test cases but um
I'm telling you all the different ways
uh or all the different options which
are available inside the requirement
section okay um so I think I have
covered almost everything which is
present inside the requirements section
um we are almost on time so if you have
got any questions then uh please post it
into the Q&A section uh this uh video
will be available after the session on
our website um and for accessing it you
need to be registered on the website and
you'll be able to go through the
recording
anytime uh so this was the requirements
management uh session where we looked at
how requirements can be built how they
can be linked and how um the
calculations are done how it uh how the
coverage specified uh is calculated how
the execution state is calculated how
the frequency damage class is used to uh
to calculate the weightage of each
requirement and how it serves as a
project dashboard right so all of these
topics are covered inside the
requirements management and how it helps
you to uh perform risk based testing
properly you can always use the print
view feature uh in the requirements
dashboard if you want to provide uh your
uh project managers a real time view of
um your project dashboard if they don't
have access to tosa then you can always
do this right
so uh this feature is present in almost
all all the different sections uh you
can do it right from here from the
requirement section as well
so uh you can you can choose the print
View and then you can direct it to any
particular format you want so it even
could be a HTML format or it could be a
PDF it could be uh Excel whatever you
want to um share right so once you
export
okay and then you can open it uh in HTML
obviously it is not the best format but
you can always adjust this uh if uh you
want you can put it in Excel and then
adjust the rows and columns accordingly
to uh have it like a report for your
management to look at uh what is your
current status of the project um mostly
the coverage specified and the execution
State okay
so yeah uh that was the last thing uh
which I wanted to say uh in the
requirements
section um if there are no other
questions then I will close the session
we have five minutes early but look out
for the upcoming upcoming webinars um I
will we will be posting it in the
website and you can register for them
they are free and they will be on
different topics uh within the rent
distar
tool yep uh there are many sessions
lined up so we will try to also cover
the UIA um if it is uh possible so but
keep looking out for the upcoming
webinars it could be on different topics
which are being asked by uh
everyone okay so thanks for joining in
um and and uh we'll talk to you guys
later on in upcoming webinars or if
you're part of the course then um you
can always interact with me um
individually yep so thanks for all of
your time and we'll talk to you soon
thank you
bye